

Kody Brown

Software Architect

CONTACT ME



(801) 310-1122



thewizard@wasatchwizard.com



West Jordan, UT 84081

LINKS

GitHub, LinkedIn, Twitter, G+, FB kodybrown

SKYPE

wasatchwizard

WEB

kodybrown.com wasatchwizard.com

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

UI/UX Design	
HTML	
CSS	
JavaScript	
Responsive Web	
C# / dotnet core	



ABOUT ME

I am passionate about technology in all its various forms. From running a large network of home-grown IoT devices, Bitcoin miners, building go-karts and electric scooters, playing with amateur (ham) radio, to converting a 44foot school bus to a mobile hacker station and RV for the family. I am exceptionally skilled across the full stack of software development and Internet of Things (IoT).

I excel in transforming complex challenges into simple and elegant solutions, while maintaining an intuitive user experience. I can focus in on the small pieces while still aware of the big picture. I lead teams through the iterative development process, ensuring secure, stable, performant, and extendable solutions.



EDUCATION

Business Management University of Phoenix

2002 - 2003

Robotics & Fabrication, Software Engineering Modesto Junior College

1992 - 1994



BUZZWORTHY

Graduated high school early

Graduated high school and started attending college at 15 years old.

Essential C#

Technical editor of (multiple editions) the Essential C# book by Mark Michaelis.

Patent #US8275895 "DHCP - establishing a trusted DHCP connection" Patent #US20180375377 "Induction powered electricity current monitoring"

WORK EXPERIENCE

Vutiliti, Inc.

Chief Technology Officer / Software Architect

Led teams to create responsive, mobile-first web apps, scalable and performant REST APIs, IoT applications, predictions using AI/ML, embedded hardware design and code, Grafana dashboards and plugins, and DevOps infrastructure. C#, Go, .Net Core, C/C++ (ARM), HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular,

Docker, Azure, Rust, Salt Stack, Ionic Android/iOS, Dart, and even some Ruby

ConsultNet 2013 - 2016 Web Architect (Consultant)

Created responsive, mobile, and desktop websites using various libraries, including vanilla JS while constantly adjusting to different teams, environments, and schedules. JavaScript, Backbone, Node, CSS, HTML, Ember.js, C#, MSSQL, C/C++ Angular.js, Sitecore CMS, Meteor, PhoneGap, Ember.js, ASP.NET MVC

Venafi, Inc. 2008 - 2013 Web Architect

Led a team in the design and implementation of a web-based PKI management console. Ensured the platform was secure against all known attacks, such as XSS and CSRF. C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MSSQL, Oracle, MySQL, C/C++

OneGreatFamily.com Web Architect

2006 - 2008

2015 - Present

Led a team of developers in creating a web-based genealogy website, including an online family tree, extensible dashboard with widgets, data mining, and more. C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Oracle, MySQL, C/C++

LANDesk Software, Inc. Senior Software Engineer

2003 - 2006

Worked on .NET web platform, Windows CE/Mobile, and BlackBerry devices. Created LANDesk Message-based SDK and Handheld Manager (over 1 million client installs). C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MSSQL, MSMQ, Java & J2ME, C/C++